The William Siegmann Collection, 1932-2007 IULC038 IULC038
Liberian Collections
- Research
  - Education
    - "The Role of Bolahun in the Educational Program of Liberia"; P.V. Konneh, undated (Box 15)
    - "A Study Program in Liberia for LCA College and University Students"; Robert Bradford, 1978 (Box 15)
    - "Timber Trees of Liberia"; University of Liberia College of Forestry (Box 15)
  - Ethnic Groups (Box 16)
    - "An Anaylsis of a Typical Tribal Power Structure in Sanniquellie District"; Mike Hohl, undated (Box 16)
    - "The Bambara"; E.J. Brill, 1974 (Box 16)
    - The Belle Tribe; Andreas Massing,, undated, 1971 (Box 16)
    - "Conceptions and Explanations of sii, Epilepsy. A Medical-Anthropological Study Among the Bassa and Kpelle in Liberia"; Corry Gerrits, 1983 (Box 16)
    - "An Eastern Kran Group in the Ivory Coast, and an Attempt at Chronology in the Kru Cultural Zone"; Joseph J. Lauer, 1974 (Box 16)
    - "Ethnic Groups and Languages", undated (Box 16)
    - "The Ethnography of the Protectorate" Book Review; Michael Banton, 1955 (Box 16)
    - "A Historian's View of Bantu Origins"; Harold G. Marcus, undated (Box 16)
    - "The Kingship in Bornu"; Ronald Cohen, 1966 (Box 16)
    - "La Mise en Place Poulations Guere et Wobe"; Alfred Scwartz,, undated, 1969 (Box 16)
      Translated into English
    - "Mutual Relations Between Loma and Mandingo In Liberia According to Oral Historical Tradition"; Karin I.S. Weisswange, undated (Box 16)
    - "Notes on the Traditional History of the Tribes in the Voinjama District of Lofa County"; Paul M. Korvah, 1971 (Box 16)
    - Notes on the Ziambli, undated (Box 16)
    - "Peoples of Africa": Notes; George Peter Murdock, undated (Box 16)
    - "The Peoples of Western Cote D'Ivoire"; Marie Noel Verger-Fevre, undated (Box 16)
    - "Political Kingdoms of the Temne"; Kenneth Wylie,, undated, 1977 (Box 16)
    - Populations of Ethnic Groups, undated, 1986 (Box 16)
    - "Pre-, Proto-, and Para- Bantu"; Nicholas David, 1971 (Box 16)
    - "A Standardization of Liberian Eithnic Nomenclature"; Svend Holsoe, 1979 (Box 16)
    - "The Temme: Their Life, Land, and Ways"; E.R. Langley, undated (Box 16)
    - "The Tribes of Liberia"; H. Bokai Freeman, undated (Box 16)
    - "The Tribes of Northern Liberia" ( 1933); Paul Germann, 1992 (Box 16)
    - "Tribes of the Western Province and the Denwoin People", 1933 (Box 16)
    - "West Atlantic Tribes and Langues of the Area"; Nicholas Pitaro, undated (Box 16)
    - "Who Are The Krahn/Guere and the Gio/Yacouba? Ethnic Identifications Along the Liberia-Ivory Coast Border"; Svend Holsoe & Joseph J. Lauer, 1976 (Box 16)
    - Bassa (Box 16)
      - "Bassa Norms and Western Influence, Nineteen Teens to the Present: A Biography of Whea Mblombagar"; Moses Baiyocitar Mady-yuu, 1984 (Box 16)
      - Bassa Political Leadership, undated (Box 16)
      - Bassa Political Leadership, undated (Box 16)
      - "Cooperative Organizations Among the Bassa"; Andreas Massing, undated (Box 16)
    - Dan (Box 16)
      - "Death ("ga") in Dan Culture: Concepts, Ceremonies and Folklore Concerning Death in North East Liberia"; George Tahmen & Wowoa W., 1974 (Box 16)
      - "Gor and Gle: Ancient Structure of Government in the Dan (Gio) Tribe"; George W.W. Tabmen, 1971 (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous Dan Svend Holsoe, undated (Box 16)
      - "The Tribe is Dan, Not Gio", 1974 (Box 16)
    - Gbandi (Box 16)
      - "Educational Insitutions"; Benjamin C. Dennis, undated (Box 16)
      - "The Gbandes: A People of the Liberian Hinterland" Book Review; Gerald E. Currens, undated (Box 16)
    - Gola (Box 16)
      - "Common Principles of Variant Kinship Structures Among the Gola of Western Liberia"; Warren d'Azevedo, undated (Box 16)
      - "Gola Womanhood and the Limits of Masculine Omnipotence"; Warren d'Azevedo, undated, 1992 (Box 16)
      - "The Setting of Gola Society and Culture"; Warren d'Azevedo, undated (Box 16)
      - "Uses of the Past in Gola Discourse"; Warren d'Azevedo, undated, 1962 (Box 16)
    - Grebo (Box 16)
      - Grebo Marriage Customs, undated (Box 16)
      - The Origin of the Grebo, undated (Box 16)
    - Kissi (Box 16)
      - Ethnographic Suvery of Liberia: The Kissi of Liberia; Andreas Massing, undated (Box 16)
      - "The Rites of Circumcision in the Kissi Country (Former French Upper Guinea)"; Andre Schaeffner,, undated, 1971 (Box 16)
    - Kpelle (Box 16)
      - Folk Tales, 1973 (Box 16)
      - "Hospital Use Among the Kpelle of Liberia"; John Patrick O'Grady, 1969 (Box 16)
      - "The Kpelle Moot: A Therapeutic Model for the Informal Settlement of Disputes"; James L Gibbs, Jr., 1963 (Box 16)
      - Kpelle Political Organization; James L Gibbs, Jr., undated (Box 16)
      - "The Kpelle View of Animal Ecology"; Alfred Kulah, 1968 (Box 16)
      - "The Kpelle Woman: Socialization and Subsistence, Symbol and Surgery"; Gerald M. Erchak, 1977 (Box 16)
      - "Marriage Among the Kpelle"; James L Gibbs, Jr., 1963 (Box 16)
      - "Primitive Government: The Case of the Kpelle of Liberia"; Richard M. Fulton, 1968 (Box 16)
      - "Secret Knowledge as Property and Power in Kpelle Society: Elders vs Youth"; William P. Murphy, undated (Box 16)
      - "Secret Medicines, Magic, and Rites of the Kpelle Tribe in Liberia"; William Welmers, 1964 (Box 16)
      - "The Social Organization of Knowledge in Kpelle Ritual"; Beryl L. Bellman, 1979 (Box 16)
      - "Traditional Cooperatives Among the Kpelle"; H. Dieter Siebel, 1969 (Box 16)
      - "Women and Marriage in Kpelle Society"; Caroline Hazel Bledsoe, 1976 (Box 16)
    - Krahn (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous Krahn, undated (Box 16)
      - "The Societies Among the Krahn (Tchien) People", undated (Box 16)
    - Kru (Box 16)
      - "Change Within the Sikleo Kru Society of Liberia with Emphasis on Marriage"; Thomas Edward Hayden, 1976 (Box 17)
      - "City, Countryside and Kru Ethnicity" ( 1991); Breitborde, L.B., 2007 (Box 17)
      - "The Economic Anthropology of the Kru"; Andreas Massing, 1980 (Box 17)
      - "A General Outline of Historical Developments Within the Kru Cultural Province"; Guenter Schroeder & Andreas Massing, 1970 (Box 17)
      - "Insitutional Change Among the Kru"; Andreas Massing, 1971 (Box 17)
      - "A Konobo Group in the Ivory Couast and Chronology in the Kru Cultural Zone"; Joseph Lauer, 1979 (Box 17)
      - "The Kru and Related Peoples, West Africa" ( 1929); Esu Biyi, undated (Box 17)
      - "The Kru Culutre Area"; Andreas Massing, undated (Box 17)
      - "Kru Emigration to British and French Guinea 1841-1857"; Monica Schuler, 1986 (Box 17)
      - Kru Politics Andreas Massing, undated (Box 17)
      - "The Kru-Speaking Groups of the Windward and Leeward Coasts in the 18th and 19th Century: Migration and Settlement"; Andreas Massing, undated (Box 17)
      - "Linguistic Evidence for Reconstruction the History of the Kru/Guere"; Joseph Lauer, undated (Box 17)
      - "Modernizing Migrants and Problems of Change in Kru Polities"; Elizabeth Tonkin, undated (Box 17)
      - "Notes and Materials on the Kru-Speakers of SE-Liberia"; Guenter Schroeder & Andreas Massing, undated (Box 17)
      - "Political Systems of the Kru in Liberia"; Andreas Massing, undated (Box 17)
      - "Preliminary Report on the Kru"; Kjell Zetterstrom, 1969 (Box 17)
      - "Religious Concepts and Institutions Among the Kru"; Andreas Massing, undated (Box 17)
      - "Social Administration of the Kru"; H. Scudder Mekeel, undated (Box 17)
      - "Socio-Political Relations Among the Kru Groups Prior to Inegration Into the Liberian State"; Andreas Massing, undated (Box 17)
      - "Structural Continuity in the Development of an Urban Kru Community"; Lawrence B. Breitborde, 1979 (Box 17)
      - "Traditional Political Organizations in the Kru Culture Area"; Andreas Massing, 1977 (Box 17)
    - Loma (Box 17)
      - "A Bibliography of Works on the Loma (Toma) in Liberia and Guinea"; Robert S. Leopold, 1981 (Box 17)
      - "The History of the Lorma Tribe"; Paul M. Koryah, undated (Box 17)
      - "The Loma Household"; Jeanette Carter, 1970 (Box 17)
      - "The Loma Soldier as a Labor Migrant"; Jeanette Carter, 1969 (Box 17)
      - "Perspective Alliance and Ritual Collaboration in Loma Society"; Robert Selig Leopold, 1991 (Box 17)
      - "The Rural Loma and Monrovia: Ties With an Urban Center"; Jeanette Carter, undated (Box 17)
    - Mandingo (Box 17)
      - "The Absence of Caste in a Mande Diaspora Population: Liberia's Mandingo"; Martin Ford, 1990 (Box 17)
      - "Mandingo Voluntary Associations in Monrovia - Some Reflections"; Geysbeek, Tim, 1988 (Box 17)
      - "A Note on the Mandingo of Western Liberia"; Warren d'Azevedo, 1969 (Box 17)
      - "Some Ethnohistorical Continuities on the Central Guinea Coast: The 'Mandingo' Phenomenon in Early Twentieth Century Scholarship"; Warren d'Azevedo, undated (Box 17)
    - Mano (Box 17)
      - Report from Liberia; Kjell Zetterstrom, undated (Box 17)
      - "Some Notes on Mano Beliefs"; Kjell Zetterstrom, 1972 (Box 17)
      - "Traditional Co-Operative Societies Among the Mano", undated (Box 17)
      - Yamein Mano; Kjell Zetterstrom, 1976 (Box 17)
      - "The Yamein Mano of Northern Liberia"; Kjell Zetterstrom, 1976 (Box 17)
    - Mende (Box 17)
      - "The Ancestral Spirits of the Mendi"; Sjoerd Hofstra,, undated, 1972 (Box 17)
      - "The Belief Among the Mendi in Non-Ancestral Spirits, and it's Relation to a Case of Parricide"; Sjoerd Hofstra, undated, 1972 (Box 17)
      - "Mende and Sherbo Women in High Office"; Carol P. Hoffer, 1972 (Box 17)
      - "Socialization in the Traditional Mende Society of Sierra Leone"; Rich Corby, undated (Box 17)
    - Sabo (Box 17)
      - "Research on the Uses of Kinship in Sabo Labor Migration"; Frederick McEvoy, undated (Box 17)
      - "Some Problems in Sabo Kinship and Community Organization"; Frederick McEvoy,, undated, 1969 (Box 17)
    - Vai (Box 17)
      - "The First Vai Migration"; Svend Holsoe, 1974 (Box 17)
      - "A Three Script Literacy Among the Vai: Arabic, English and Vai"; Mohamed B. Nyei, 1981 (Box 17)
      - "The Vai of Liberia: Selected Studies"; Svend Holsoe, 1980 (Box 17)
  - Foreign Language Materials (Box 17)
    Please see archivist for complete list of titles. Majority of folders are in Dutch, Spanish, and German.
  - History
    - 1979 Liberian Race Riots (Box 21)
    - "66th Anniversary of the Founding of Maryland in Liberia" ( 1900); S.A.O. Thomson, undated (Box 21)
    - "The Achievement and Early Consequences of Food Production"; Robert J. Braidwood & Charles A. Reed, 1957 (Box 21)
    - "Africa and the American Flag" ( 1854); Andrew J. Foote, undated (Box 21)
    - "African Kings and their Royal Relatives"; Audrey Richards, 1961 (Box 21)
    - "African Slavery and Other Forms of Social Oppression on the Upper Guinea Coast in the Context of the Atlantic Slave-Trade"; Walter Rodney, 1966 (Box 21)
    - African Squadron Papers ( 1848-1851 ), undated (Box 21)
    - "Americans in Africa 1865-1900 "; Clarence Clendenen, Robert Collins & Peter Duignan, 1966 (Box 21)
    - Alfred Tulk's Diary, 1931 (Box 21)
    - "Americans in Black Africa"; Clarence Clendenen & Peter Duignan, 1964 (Box 21)
    - "An Account of the Liberian Hinterland c. 1780 " ( 1808); P.E.H. Hair, 1962 (Box 21)
    - "Ancient Egypt and Black Africa"; David O'Conner, 1971 (Box 21)
    - "Anthropology and History: The African Case"; Daniel F. McCall, 1970 (Box 21)
    - "An Appraisal of British Imperial Policy with Respect to the Extraction of Mineral Resources in Nigeria"; Edwin G. Charles, Jr., 1964 (Box 21)
    - "Avenues Towards Modernization in Tribal Liberia"; David Blanchard, undated (Box 21)
    - "A Biographical Approach to Nineteenth Century Buganda History"; John A. Rowe, 1966 (Box 21)
    - "B. J. K. Anderson Revisited: An Inquiry into Historical Evidence"; Jane Jackson Martin & C. E. Zamba Liberty, undated (Box 21)
    - "Black Loyalists in Search of the Promised Land"; Hassan Sisay, undated (Box 21)
    - Chicago Columbian Exposition (Liberian Commissioners) ( 1893 ); Hon. Alfred B King & Hon. William E. Rothery, undated (Box 21)
    - "A Chronological Outline of Events Significant to the Emergence of a Liberian Nation"; Warren L. d'Azevedo, undated (Box 21)
    - "Comparison of African Kingdoms"; J. Vansina, 1962 (Box 21)
    - "Comparitive Efficiency of Regulation or Abolition, as Applied to the Slave Trade " ( 1789); Rev. T. Clarkson, undated (Box 21)
    - "The Day Monrovia Stood Still: April 14, 1979"; Albert Porte (Box 21)
    - "Early American Methodism, Vol. One"; Wade Crawford Barclay, 1949 (Box 21)
    - "Edward James Roye and His Family, a Portrait of a Black Midwestern Man During the First Half of the Nineteenth Cenury"; Svend Holsoe, 1970 (Box 21)
    - Encyclopaedia Britannica Entries 'Liberia' & 'Monrovia'; Philip Wayland Porter & William Richard Stanley, 1970 (Box 21)
    - "Emily Tubman, Her Slaves and the President of Liberia, William V. S. Tubman"; Svend Holsoe, 1969 (Box 21)
    - "Ethnic Movements and Acculturation in Upper Guinea Since the Fifteenth Century"; Yves Person, 1970 (Box 21)
    - "Ethnoarchaeology in Africa"; John H. Atherton, 1983 (Box 21)
    - "Ethnohistorical Studies of the Kru Coast"; Ron Davis, undated (Box 21)
    - "Excavations at Kamabai and Yagala Rock Shelters, Sierra Leone"; John H. Atherton, 1972 (Box 21)
    - "A Full Description of the African Field of the P.E. Church" ( 1866), undated (Box 21)
    - "A General History of the Pyrates" ( 1734); Capt. Charles Johnson, undated (Box 21)
    - "Grown Up Liberia"; Francis Mitchell, 1945 (Box 21)
    - "Gew FéKpe: Newsorgan of the Movement for Justice in Africa (MOJA) Special Issue May 25, 1979 " (Box 21)
    - "History of the Garraway People and of the Mission Hilltop"; R. L. Embree, 1930 (Box 21)
    - "History of Liberia"; Thomas H.B. Walker, 1921 (Box 21)
    - "Intro To Karnga Manuscripts"; Svend Holsoe, 1970 (Box 21)
    - "Iron in the Central West Atlantic Region of West Africa"; John A. Price, 1962 (Box 21)
    - "The Kru Coast in Maritime History"; Andreas Massing, undated (Box 21)
    - "The Kru Mariner: An Historical Compendium"; George E. Brooks, 1970 (Box 21)
    - "Land and Power in Liberia"; Leon Weintraub, 1970 (Box 21)
    - "The Late Neolithic and the Question of State Formation in the Western Sudan"; Patrick Munson, 1969 (Box 21)
    - "The Lebanese in West Africa"; Marwan Hanna, 1961 (Box 21)
    - "The Lebanese in West Africa"; R. Bayly Winder, 1962 (Box 21)
    - "Liberia" ( 1942); R.A. de Lynden, 1973 (Box 21)
    - "Liberia as I Found It in 1858"; Alexander Cowan, undated (Box 21)
    - "Liberia, Germany, Britain, and the United States, 1905-1918"; Wolfe W. Schmokel, 1976 (Box 21)
    - "Liberia: The Americo-African Republic"; Thomas Stewart, undated (Box 21)
    - "Liberian Boundary Problems", Paul Hirning, undated (Box 21)
    - "Liberian Coast to 1820"; Svend Holsoe, 1961 (Box 21)
    - "Liberian Social History: Establishing the Settler Standard"; Tom W. Schick, 1976 (Box 21)
    - "Liberia's Boundaries from the 1700s to 1911"; Reed Stewart, 1969 (Box 21)
    - "The Liberian Frontier Force 1908-1962"; Harrison Akingbade, 1977-1978 (Box 21)
    - Liberia Timeline, 1961 (Box 21)
    - Liberian Historical Review, Volumes I-III, 1964 (Box 21)
    - Liberian Historical Review, Volumes IV-V, 1968-1969 (Box 21)
    - Liberian History Notes Susan Mitchell, 1953 (Box 21)
    - "Limba War Caves"; John Atherton, 1968 (Box 21)
    - "Lincoln and His Wife's Home Town"; William H. Townsend, 1929 (Box 21)
    - "Lofa County in Historical Perspective"; Sylvester Corker & Samuel Massaquoi, undated (Box 21)
    - "The Mani Invasions of Liberia and Sierra Leone in Larger Perspective"; Geroge E. Brooks (Box 21)
    - "The Massaquoi Family of Liberia, Siera Leone and the United States: Making Connections on Three Continents"; Rob Leopold, 1994 (Box 21)
    - "Mbawalume's Campaign and the Kailahun Question"; Andreas Massings, undated (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous History ( 1822-1834 ), undated (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous Slave Trade, undated (Box 21)
    - "The Native Problem in Africa"; Raymond Buell, 1965 (Box 21)
    - "The Ngoni: A Military Conquest State"; Philip Walken, 1969 (Box 21)
    - "Notes on Africa; Particularly Those Parts Which are Situated Between Cape Verd and the River Congo" ( 1819); G.A> Robertson, undated (Box 21)
    - "Notes on Some Members of the Learned Classes of Zanzibar and East Africa in the 19th Century"; B.G. Martin, undated (Box 21)
    - "'Old Bruin': Commodor Matthew C. Perry 1784-1858 "; Sameul Eliot Morison, 1967 (Box 21)
    - "On the Republic of Liberia, Its Products and Resources" ( 1862); Gerald Ralston, undated (Box 21)
    - "Palmares: An African State in Brazil"; R.K. Kent, 1965 (Box 21)
    - "Pawning of Human Beings in Liberia"; Christy Cuthbert, 1931 (Box 21)
    - "The People of Africa" ( 1871); E.W. Blyden & Tayler Lewis, 1995 (Box 22)
    - Porte, Albert - Articles, 1965-1974 (Box 22)
    - "Protestants as Pirates, Slavers, and Proto-Missionaires: Sierra Leone, 1568 and 1582"; P.E.H. Hair, 1970 (Box 22)
    - "The Puzzle of Primitive People"; Michael Cole, 1968 (Box 22)
    - "Research on Liberian Traditional History"; Svend Holsoe, 1962 (Box 22)
    - "The Resistance Against Apartheid in South Africa"; William J. Pomeroy, 1971 (Box 22)
    - "Samuel W. Seton, Liberian Citizen"; Jane Martin, 1970 (Box 22)
    - "Scenes of Everyday Life in Africa"; Harriet Britton, undated (Box 22)
    - "The Search for Matilda Newport"; Jane Martin, 1976 (Box 22)
    - "Sketches of Liberia: Comprising a Brief Account of the Geography, Climate, Productions, and Diseases of the Republic of Liberia" ( 1853), J.W. Lugenbeel, 1963 (Box 22)
    - "Slaves from the Windward Coast"; Adam Jones & Marion Johnson, 1980 (Box 22)
    - "Slave Trading in the Vai Area of Sierra Lenon and Liberia"; Svend E. Holsoe, 1973 (Box 22)
    - "Some French Sources on Upper Guinea 1540-1575 "; P.E.H Hair, 1969 (Box 22)
    - "Some Historical Problems in the Delineation of a Central West Atlantic Region"; Warren d'Azevedo, 1962 (Box 22)
    - "Theodore Canot at Cape Mount 1841-1847 "; Svend E. Holsoe, 1975 (Box 22)
    - "Thompson's West Africa", undated (Box 22)
    - "Towards an Ethnohistory of Nimba County, Liberia"; Andreas Massing & Joseph Yeanney, undated (Box 22)
    - "Traditional Cities of Africa"; Daniel McCall, undated (Box 22)
    - "A Transplanted World: Black Americans in West Africa"; Svend Holsoe, 1988 (Box 22)
    - "Upper Guinea and the Significance of the Origins of Africans Enslaved in the New World"; Walter Rodney, 1969 (Box 22)
    - "Vase Kamara's History of the Founding of Musadu", 1990 (Box 22)
    - "Views and Suggestions of Concerned Ministers of the Gospel" (Rice Riots), 1979 (Box 22)
    - "War In Liberia", 1936 (Box 22)
    - "West Atlantic Circle"; Baumann & Westerman, 1948 (Box 22)
    - "Western Africa: Its History, Condition and Prospects" ( 1856; J. Leighton Wilson, undated (Box 22)
    - "The White Man's Task in Tropical Africa"; Sir Frederick D. Lugard, 1926 (Box 22)
    - "Zanzibar and the Coastal Belt 1840-1884 "; J.M. Gray, undated (Box 22)
    - "Zwedru Station Handbook"; Svend Holsoe & Lovette Azango, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Linguistics
    - Bambara-English Student Lexicon; Charles Bird & Mamadou Kante, 1977 (Box 22)
    - Bandi-English Dictionary; Rev Josepn Parsell, 1966 (Box 22)
    - Bandi Language Learning Materials, undated (Box 22)
    - "The Basa Spelling Book" ( 1840 ); Ivory Clarke, undated (Box 22)
    - "Basic Dyula"; Ronald W. Long, undated (Box 22)
    - Bassa and English Phrases, undated, 1971 (Box 22)
    - Bassa and Kissi Word Listsundated, 1951 (Box 22)
    - "Bassa-English Dictionary"; June Hobley, undated (Box 22)
    - Bassa Language Learning Materials, undated (Box 22)
    - Bassa Lessons Laubach, undated (Box 22)
    - "A Bibliography of Liberian Languages"; Frances Ingemann, undated (Box 22)
    - "A Bibliography of the Vai Language and Script"; Gail Stewart & P.E.H. Hair, 1969 (Box 22)
    - "Black English Over Yonder: A Study of Liberian Settler English"; John Victor Singler, undated (Box 22)
    - "A Case of Stimulus Diffusion? Note on Possible Connections Between The Vai and Cherokee Scripts"; Svend Holsoe, undated (Box 22)
    - "Christ Our Savior" Translated into Bassa" (1843), undated (Box 22)
    - "Classification and Thought" (Kpelle); John Gay, undated (Box 22)
    - "The Contribution of Early Linguistic Material to the History of West Africa"; P.E.H. Hair, 1970 (Box 22)
    - "The Development of Mandekan (Manding): A Study of the Role of Extra-linguistic Factors in Linguistic Change"; Charles S. Bird,, undated, 1970 (Box 22)
    - "Early Liberian Achievements in Linguistics"; Sara Lou Merry, undated (Box 22)
    - "An Early 17th Century Vocabulary of Vai"; P.E.H. Hair, undated (Box 22)
    - "Ethnolinguistic Continuity on the Guinea Coast"; P.E.H. Hair, 1967 (Box 22)
    - "An Ethnolinguistic Inventory of the Lower Guinea Coast Before 1700: pt 1 and 2"; P.E.H. Hair, 1968-1969 (Box 22)
    - "Ethnolinguistic Inventory of Upper Guinea Coast Before 1700"; P.E.H. Hair, undated (Box 22)
    - Gola Script - Adanta Lymus, undated (Box 22)
    - "Guide to Transcription and Pronunciation"; Warren d'Azevedo, undated (Box 22)
    - "The Historical Problem fo the Indigenous Scripts of West Africa and Surinam"; David Dalby, 1970 (Box 22)
    - "Introduction to Liberian Country English", undated (Box 22)
    - "Kpelle Language Training Manuel", 1975 (Box 22)
    - "Kpelle Uses of Kpelle Logic"; John Gay, undated (Box 22)
    - Kruan Languages, undated (Box 22)
    - "Kruan Languages in Liberia"; Frances Ingemann, 1972 (Box 22)
    - "Kru Grammar and Lessons"; Clark Yates, 1967 (Box 22)
    - "The Kru Languages: A Progress Report"; William Welmers, 1977-1982 (Box 22)
    - "Kwa Speaking Peoples of Liberia", 1977 (Box 22)
    - "Language and Tribe Among Government School Students in Monrovia: A Preliminary Report"; James C. Borg, 1969 (Box 23)
    - Language Booklets, undated (Box 23)
    - " 'Le Langaigee de Guynee': A Sixteenth Century Vocabulary From the Pepper Coast"; David Dalby & P.E.H. Hair, 1964 (Box 23)
    - "Lexicography for the Wee", Janet Stanley, 1999 (Box 23)
    - "Liberian Cultural English"; Tom Mercer, undated (Box 23)
    - "Liberian Languages"; John Duitsman, 1982 (Box 23)
    - "Liberia's Heritage of African Language"; William Welmers, undated (Box 23)
    - Loma, undated, 1973 (Box 23)
    - Mande Language Classification, undated (Box 23)
    - "Manual for the Kru Languages"; James Koffa & B.K. Tah Noe, undated (Box 23)
    - Medical Phrases in Loma, undated (Box 23)
    - "The Mel Languages: A Reclassification of Southern 'West Atlantic'"; David Dalby, 1965 (Box 23)
    - "The Mena Family of Languages" ( 1858 ); William H.I. Bleek, undated (Box 23)
    - Mende Lessons, undated (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 23)
    - "Niger-Congo, Mande"; William Welmers, 1971 (Box 23)
    - "The Northern Mande Languagues: A Statistical Pretesting of 22 Idolects"; Ronald W. Long, 1971 (Box 23)
    - "Occasions for Use of a Kpelle Classification System"; John Gay & Michael Cole, 1969 (Box 23)
    - "Practical Orthography of African Languages", undated (Box 23)
    - "Progress in the Study of the Vai Script"; Gail Stewart & P.E.H. Hair, 1969 (Box 23)
    - "A Reevaluation of The Linguistic Classification of the Kru-Speaking Peoples"; Patrick Bennett, 1974 (Box 23)
    - "A Short Vai-English Dictionary"; Tom Wheeler, undated (Box 23)
    - "Social Organization and Language Spread: The Liberian Case"; L.B. Breitborde, 1979 (Box 23)
    - "Some Liberian English Usages"; Warren d'Azevedo & William Welmers (Box 23)
    - "Some Linguistic Evidence in the Study of Kru Ethnolinguistic Affiliation; L.B. Breitborde, undated (Box 23)